Guide to the Truman Seymour Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Truman Seymour papers
1859-1885
MS 993
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
The papers consist chiefly of six sketchbooks of drawings and watercolors of Italian scenes and copies of old masters made by Truman Seymour after his retirement to Italy in 1876. Also included are two notebooks from 1885.
Seymour, Truman, 1824-1891
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Irene Weir in 1935.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Truman Seymour: instructor in drawing at West Point, brevent Major General in Civil War, amateur artist.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist chiefly of six sketchbooks of drawings and watercolors of Italian scenes and copies of old masters made by Truman Seymour after his retirement to Italy in 1876. Also included are two notebooks from 1885.
Americans -- Italy; Art; Drawing -- 19th century; Watercolor painting; Artists; Seymour, Truman, 1824-1891
- Inventory
  Scope and Contents
  The Truman Seymour Papers consist of six sketchbooks and notebooks. Most of the sketches are pencil drawings, although there are also some watercolors. The drawings are either generally copies of the old masters or sketches of Italian scenes. The papers were donated to Yale University by Irene Weir in 1935. The Truman Seymour sketchbooks originally belonged to Robert W. Weir, professor of drawing at the United States Military Academy and father-in-law of Seymour.
  For additional Truman Seymour material, see the John Ferguson Weir Papers (MS 550). The Weir Papers contain eight Truman Seymour letters.
  - Sketchbooks
    - [1859?] (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1881 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1881-1882 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1882 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1882, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1885 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Notebooks
    - [1885?] (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1885 (Box 1, Folder 8)